# 不就烧饼加肉吗
So, just Shaobing and grounded meat. That’s pretty predictable.
# 不是加肉 哥
You would think, brother.
# 这叫圆梦烧饼
This is Cixi Shaobing.
# 圆了慈禧一个梦
This Shaobing brings Empress Dowager Cixi’s dream to life!
# 圆梦烧饼
So we call it Yuan Meng (“dream come true”) Shaobing.
# 先和面吧大爷 先和面
Let’s make the dough first, Da Ye.
# 中筋粉 一斤
1 jin (500g) All-purpose Flour
# 酵母8克
8 g Yeast
# 白糖是60克
60g Cane Sugar
# 水是四两九
4 liang 9 qian (245g) Water
# 温水吧得 温水温水
Have to use warm water. Warm water.
# 全是标准
Talking about standard.
# 给它化开了 酵母
Resolve the yeast in water.
# 冬天天凉多放点酵母没事
Since it’s winter (cold), it’s ok to use more yeast here.
# 这就是一关键点
This actually a key point.
# 一定要多放点
You gotta use more yeast.
# 夏天就放5克就够了
If you are making this in summer (hot), 5g is enough.
# 什么程度是软面呀
What makes it a soft dough?
# 稍微硬一点
We need to knead it to just a bit harder.
# 跟饺子面差不多
(soft dough here) is similar to the dough for Jiaozi skin (Chinese dumpling skin).
# 老佛爷怎么想起
How comes CIxi think of…
# 要吃肉末烧饼
Eating Shaobing stuffed with grounded meat?
# 老佛爷做的梦啊
It’s in Cixi’s dream.
# 老佛爷做梦 您都知道
Oh like you would know Cixi had a dream.
# 梦见
Yea.
# 用这火烧夹这肉沫一吃
She dreamed of eating Shaobing (the actual name referred here is “Huoshao”, which is a type of Chinese Shaobing) stuffed with ground meat.
# 第二天的御膳房呢
The second day,
# 恰巧就做了一个肉末
The Imperial kitchen actually prepared such a dish for her
# 这么巧
In such a coincident,
# 最后这老佛爷的梦就圆了
Cixi’s dream comes true.
# 不就烧饼加肉 吗
So, just Shaobing and grounded meat. That’s pretty predictable.
# 不是加肉 哥
You would think, brother.
# 这叫圆梦烧饼
This is Cixi Shaobing.
# 圆梦圆了慈禧一个梦
This Shaobing brings Empress Dowager Cixi’s dream to life!
# 这是芯
This is the dough putting inside the wrapper.
# 芯里面还有油 对放点油
There is oil on the dough. Pour some oil.
# 空心烧饼就是
Oh so that creates the hollow effect for Shaobing
# 好加肉沫 加的肉沫多一些
Yes exactly. Much easier to add more grounded meat.
# 你看这
Look at this
# 干面点的就是不一样
That’s years of experience in Chinese pastry.
# 揪的匀啊
He can divide the dough so equally with just bare hands
# 好 和完了面
Ok, now we have the dough ready.
# 直接揪出来小芯 不用饧这个
Now we are making the smaller doughs to put inside. No need to proof them.
# 做完成品直接饧烧饼就行
Don’t proof it until finishing making the entire pastry dough.
# 这放点油不粘
Add some oil so it won’t stick.
# 这芯好扣往外
In addition, we will find it easy to remove the inside dough after baking.
# 拿的时候好拿
Easy to remove.
# 这小活干的漂亮
That’s a neat skill!
# 蘸芝麻
Dip the dough into the sesame bowl on one side.
# 糖水容易粘 要是白水不行
But first we need to dip it into the sugar water (the plain water won’t work), so that the sesame will stay.
# 你看没有
Look
# 就这样就行了
This would work.
# 对
Yep
# 直接饧发就行
Then we can proof the doughs
# 亮子你发现没有
Liangzi, did you notice…
# 他这个酵母啊
That the quantity of the yeast…
# 来的大 酵母的量大
is large enough…
# 所以它就涨发
So that the dough rose well
# 一般都是5克
We usually use 5 g yeast
# 他加了8克
He used 8 g
# 他量加了 比原来更暄了
He used more so the dough comes out softer and ligher
# 好了
Ok
# 饧着吧 饧40分钟
Let the doughs proof for 40 min
# 就放这里面饧着
They can stay here
# 不能让它干了
We can’t let them dry
# 你看看这家庭这个多省事
See this is so convenient for DIY at your home kitchen
# 好了 烧饼发好了
Ok, the doughs are ready for the oven!
# 真好看 真圆乎啊
They are beautiful! So round!
# 放这里啊
Let’s put them here.
# 放一会儿 烤箱先升上温
Let’s wait till the oven is warm enough.
# 你看这胖乎乎的
Look how cute and chubby they are
# 这有点像大爷的小肚子
Just like Da Ye’s belly
# 胖乎乎的
Cute and chubby
# 230 升好温度
230 Celsius Degree
# 烤多久呢
For how long?
# 烤15分钟
Bake for 15 min
# 有时候看着点
But you will need to watch
# 家庭的温度跟温度不一样
Everyone has a different oven
# 你可以看着它
You can check the dough out from time to time
# 好嘞 烧饼好了师父
Ok, the Shaobings are ready, Master Chef!
# 烧饼好了
Shaobings are ready!
# 这烧饼烤的好
Beautifully baked.
# 小亮 你看这烧饼
Xiao Liang, look at this Shaobing
# 胖嘟嘟的多像你啊
As chubby as you
# 这烧饼今儿烤的嘿
The quality of the Shaobing today is…
# 比大爷的一点都不带次的
…almost like Da Ye’s master piece!
# 师父您帮我炒肉馅吧 师父
Master Chef, please help me fry the grounded meat!
# 让您露一手
Please show us the master skill.
# 我们要好好学学 学一下
We can’t wait to learning from you!
# 您这是好 老佛爷肉馅夹馍
It's great! Empress Dowager's bun with meat.
# 老佛爷圆梦烧饼
Empress Dowager's Dreaming Shao Bing
# 这肉啊有一个
A trick to frying the grounded meat
# 必须得炒酥它
Is to fry it to crispy
# 炒不酥它不好吃
It’s not as tasty if you don’t fry it till crispy.
# 你看啊 颜色
Look, the color
# 由红变白
It changes from red to white
# 这肉馅是猪肉馅 这是猪肉馅的
The grounded meat here is pork
# 肥三瘦七 对 肥三瘦七
70% lean.  Yes, 70%
# 我猜对了
I was right!
# 加10分
Bingo!
# 太肥了没法吃 腻得慌
If the meat is too fat, it will be too greasy to eat
# 太瘦了吧 它就发柴 没有香气
If the meat is too lean, it will be tough and lack of flavor
# 我记得我上学的时候
I remember when I was in school
# 老师让背口诀
The cuilinary instructor asked us to recite the formula
# 这个料 就这么点料
There were only a few sets of condiments
# 酱油料酒醋
soy, cooking wine, vinegar
# 咸盐味之素
salt and msg
# 糖辣葱姜蒜
sugar, chili, green onion, ginger, garlic
# 淀粉勾点芡
starch to thicken
# 很简单你知道吗
So simple you know.
# 煸酥煸香
We are frying it to be crispy and aromatic
# 你看开始出油了
Look the oils are coming out
# 锅也不邋遢
The wok doesn’t look messy
# 这就是煸肉馅的一个过程
This is the process of frying the grounded meat to be a viable meat filling
# 所以说必须得煸酥了
You have to fry it to crispy
# 你们来一点儿尝尝
Have a taste
# 我可不来 太烫
I can’t do it. It’s too hot.
# 我说他呀
Oh I meant to ask him.
# 这将来是你的活儿呀
This is the skill you will master and pass on in the future.
# 酥了吧
Crispy enough?
# 这是啥 师父
What is this, Master?
# 马蹄 马蹄丁
Diced water chestnut
# 今儿可以多搁点
I can put more today
# 来点姜 扔进去
Give me some ginger. Throw them in.
# 少来一点 别太多了
Just enough. Not too much
# 再来点葱花
Some diced green onion
# 增加点香气
This adds in more aroma
# 亮子 给我加点料酒
Liang Zi, give me some Chinese cooking wine
# 再来点
Some more
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 来给一点糖吧
A bit of sugar
# 来一点胡椒 来点盐
A little white pepper, and some salt
# 这就行了
That will do
# 真香 行 好咯
So aromatic! Ok! Ready to serve!
# 来 看看这烧饼
Back to the Shaobing
# 烧饼片开
Open it up…
# 一刨为二
…from the middle
# 看着啊 扥出来了啊
Look, I am taking the heart dough out
# 里边看到了吗这个 一拿
Did you see this? Now take it out.
# 圆梦烧饼
Yuan Meng Shaobing!
# 一人一个
One for each person
# 咱们一块吃啊
Let’s taste it together!
# 你看大爷
Look at Da Ye
# 炒的酥香吧
Crispy and aromatic, right?
# 真好吃
So yummy
# 好吃
Tasty
# 肉馅炒的到位了
The meat filling is on point.
# 咱再说点不足
Though there is still room for improvement.
# 面团和烧饼
The inside dough and the Shaobing
# 分离有点有点粘连
were not so easily separated as expected
# 这点小细节上
This is a small detail
# 我觉得是面团的问题
I think it is the problem of the dough
# 还是油少的问题
We should add enough oil
# 希望元国下一次
Let’s make it better next time.
# 这种现象不能出现
Can’t let this happen again
# 为什么出现这种状态你知道吗
But why exactly this happened?
# 你是一个面团
The dough you used
# 你这面团是发面的
Is a leavened dough
# 你应该做死面的
You should have made an unleavened version.